now let's try this again slightly better
let's try to move it
all right that kind of works I upgraded
the app no no no no without doing a new
product I'm good good good I'm glad it's
better no I'm not switching streaming
platforms if periscope doesn't work
that's just it for that's just it for
streaming because reddit's a waste of
time no there's a new product is Monday
is today Monday does it look like Monday
um you know what I'm happy with a CEO
I'm never gonna deal with hiring people
or managing people again I hate that
I'm not really a fan of people you
know I like technology technology's
pretty cool so I got a few things to do
all your Geo hot signs box that's right
that's right
we did we did box now I'm I'm doing
marketing today I just have to kind of
cool things to show off for research how
long Eon and new product share the exact
same codebase
so don't worry about that Eon will be
supported for exactly as long as new
product is supported get off don't type
well open piles driving you get off the
phone level two bros level two who's
tired this guy's tired Davin engineer
that's right that's right can you have
statistics what do you want statistics
about miles of autonomous mode let me
see if I can do
I want to show you all of these when I
was broken that day some of these I can
show you
let's do last six months
so these are daily miles driven
is our graph of daily miles driven so
you can see that it's up around do about
14 K miles per day so that's pretty good
and then yes that's about 14 K miles per
day and then I'll show you the other
graph so this is percent miles engaged
that looks like that but it's not too
broken so we're engaged about 50% of the
time so about 50% of the time
open pilot is actually doing the driving
miles wise so we do about 7k autonomous
miles per day cool cool cool
begin though so I have two things to
show you today first off this so this is
what we're gonna be showing off we were
hoping to have a Maps launch ready by
the thing oh I don't know about that
stuff but you can check out the maps
they're kind of beautiful right yeah you
see the lanes so these are all the
things they're localized and the zipper
still has major bugs in it we gotta
figure out but so you can see these are
all the orb features that are being used
all these all these blueish dots yeah
and this is just like what resolution
will the maps be we're trying to make an
accurate to 10 centimeters so you can
see like these lanes have a lot of
spread and variance but the average of
the lanes is quite good because that you
can see that it is galaxies so you have
Gaussian distributions on these lanes we
can improve the zipper and fix this a
little bit oh yeah Tesla Tesla the six
months to a year ahead of us they always
have been and just unless they stumbled
a there there won't be a change look you
can see like someone changed lanes here
aah yeah hopefully if the Maps done what
Willie says at the end of the year um so
you guys know to everybody who works at
a mapping company Oh what are the maps
gonna ask not ask not what maps can do
for you but what you can do for maps
let's say just Shefford plus user on
camera if you turn it on
okay shiver'd plus an open pilot are the
same code base the only difference is
that schiffer plus is read-only it
doesn't output anything to your car um
goldstar miles yeah you know we have
that internally yeah someday we'll
expose it I don't know guys
I worked in research now I don't do any
of that stuff I'll show you this other
tool I was playing with I was pretty
cool so this tool lets me visualize
episodes and what the model was say it
and give it a little bit made what
so don't be racist look at these little
episodes all right she can see this
episode so this is just five seconds of
driving up the highway
well you're hacking my computer your
band - no more hacking for you who's hi
what hi it was brah
you talkin about me you want to be man
and ones getting banned today look at
this look at it okay so that's like
the path over time so this one it works
pretty well but we can see ones where it
messes up a little bit more so let's
wait for the next one to load and these
let you explore in terms of five-second
episodes that turn just pretty well well
yeah so right now the field of view is
just the the red rectangle um but big
model uses the whole thing let's see
what we got can we build maps from night
logs yes of everything I don't think we
exclude the night once I don't think it
matters that much
um I mean most of the alignment stuff is
done okay look you can see a little bit
of behavioral cloning here that's
because the user shifts a little to the
left in the line you started some dill
kind of exciting yeah let's see let's
see what that goes yeah so we have we
have maps beautiful maps this is only
one we're using s2 tiles this is only
one s two tile you can see this side the
processing is broken but it's hard to
get this stuff to work well we'll do it
people always that's a stupid question
why do people matter explain this to me
like you asked that question
hang on so I think you asked that
question is like a proxy question for
how productive is research I have no
idea why you think number of people
correlates with productivity right
number doesn't matter I think that we
might have the first real release of
like large-scale HD maps I don't think
other companies have this and with
nothing this was smart we think about it
at what point might new hardware be on
its way to data no it's not I know it's
not your intention don't worry you're
not bad
the banhammer is coming out today though
you know I'm really I'm really an
abandoned people kind of mood what are
you doing with the map well we're making
it beautiful and precise and accurate um
no you know what the idea is right so
right now we have a level-two driving
system and there's always going to be
level two you gotten feedback from other
companies do I look like the kind of guy
who asks some people for feedback oh
yeah feedback might as well read the
internet comments oh that's what I'm
doing right now
don't you think Wow I'm leaving the
internet comments you guys are internet
comments mapping the whole world is a
big job yes for computers for people we
just write the code we don't write bad
code and then we run it it's a big Map
Reduce on the world it's literally a Map
Reduce
and it makes a match see what I'm saying
just big model incorporate time little
model incorporates time little model
uses ten frames of context you are scope
is that's true you're not random
internet commenters I know some of you
yes almost a I want to show off this map
and this tool
not only I'm not worried about other
companies stealing my maps they won't
even be stealing right like this is a
stupid way to think about it like okay
let me tell you something if you have if
you have a diamond ring
all right on your finger and somebody
steals your diamond ring you no longer
have a diamond ring if we have maps and
somebody else uses our maps guess what
we still have Matt nothing was stolen
the world just got better
intellectual property is the biggest
like okay this isn't this isn't this
isn't the twitch this isn't which we
don't we're not gonna go off on rants
like that um but no no no I'm so not
concerned about companies stealing my
map we're gonna give the maps away free
I'm not sure that I think we're gonna do
something like Creative Commons
Attribution because I do like the idea
of everybody using I'm having to stick
come AI and there I do kind of like that
so we might reserve that right
we might reserve that right justjust you
gotta say like yo man come AI coming
eyes is lit go to shop that copy that
about products liability
oh no I'm definitely disclaiming all
that don't use this map for
anything I don't even trust that if you
look at the map and you're epileptic and
it gives you a seizure I'm waiving all
that liability that's on you man
so yeah maybe well we'll do that too
maybe that'll be can we do the maps
under the MIT license now but I want
attribution does that my to license have
attribution I don't even know oh my kara
lies about attribution but I don't want
like Google using my maps without like
sticking that Google won't use my maps
Google actually has good Maps but you
know losers might use the maps and on
the mall to be like yeah them commie
guys maps all right let's read this MIT
license yes the above copyright notice
should be included in all substantial
parts of the software excellent perfect
people thank you about the quality of
the map will be pretty high-quality
don't be as high-quality as anybody
else's especially so we're doing
highways first yeah yeah what make it
downloadable how can your device control
the car brewery the code I don't know
what to say about that let's look at it
more
ah are we still focused I don't know
what that means yes you always have to
keep your eyes on the road
yes 104 is a scam it's sad that we only
have this one little area now well you
know we also have this who can't show
you that we haven't got any sales yet
today that's true
has anyone approached me from Bosch let
me tell ya so first off I'm not CEO
anymore if somebody from Bosch wants to
approach the new CEO he might be a
little more kind if somebody from Bosch
approach to me I'd be like okay for
everybody else they're free but for you
ten thousand dollars maybe ten thousand
dollars and then you could use the maps
you could also use the maps for free but
if it would make you feel more
comfortable paying me money you can pay
me money no no the maps aren't for you
to look at therefore open pilot to look
at and no you can't look at the maps
while you're driving no no it hasn't
really gotten better oh I know where I'm
going yeah we can say this stuff as well
yeah yeah they can buy some I don't know
man
if the new CEO is gonna do scary
business models like this I'm fine with
that
there we go cool
oh yeah this is like the whole Bay Area
so like all of that stuff you saw in
that one little area we have for the
entire thing
we just haven't you know well there's a
few issues with releasing map explore
apparently these tiles are of course USA
only we love America I'm apparently
these tiles the terrain tiles are loaded
from cesium and you have to pay a lot of
money to license them so we're gonna
like try to put it on map box or
something I don't know hasn't been
driven yeah we'll eventually do that you
guys want to see model bugs we can find
model bugs I have a cool list of model
bugs we can look at - yeah say lucky
you see that you see that span you can
see why it's happening the model there
yes starts to predict the lane change
I'll first say go straight but it's like
no you want to change lanes right you
can see this behavior here as the model
eventually gets to a point where it says
go straight when it's trying to pull you
back into the lane you get lyft or uber
drivers to map for me well this is the
debugging model tool alright so I could
show you guys you want to see the list
to my official research lip
neither sm PE and dil that's what's on
my official research list we should
write official research but we also
bought these new markers if you remember
me getting angry at markers on previous
ones throw a little scary and
intimidating looking so let's do
official oh this is so solid research
let's go order together no so unordered
list look it has dots it doesn't have
numbers it's an official official
research list
guys but actually eons aren't sold out
yet we have kept two eons left let me
bring up this webpage and then I can
show it to you because I can't show you
the pages in the meantime lidar is a
scam no look I mean look man that's the
thing you know maybe sometimes when I
say things like I like to say things
that are provocative because they get
the people going but the truth when you
say something like lidar is a scam
there's a one-hour conversation behind
that that actually talks about a lot of
nuance right so whether light lighter is
a scam lighter is not a scam what what
is this is this like is this like to
team politics the truth about lidar is
there's two worlds who are potentially
living there's one world where lidar
technology becomes cheap and ubiquitous
before computer vision gets good at
perception there's another world where
computer vision gets good at perception
before lidar can be mass-marketed i
think we live in world too right
i think we live in a world where
perception is actually already almost as
good as lidar and you know the only like
this was not true obviously in 2007
they were doing the dark urban challenge
and stuff derp Grand Challenge but today
things are different because we have
deep learning okay cool
yeah
to eons by eons we have two left I don't
know that's it that's most of the day's
periscopes could be a short one today he
used to tell me how long I was scoping
for and now it doesn't say about anymore
can you recommend your chair yes this
chair makes you better gamer yes it
makes you a better gamer no but uh yeah
I know long scope is there long scope is
your over
scope is were on their way out why by
yawn instead of new product even when
new product comes out it won't work as
well as he on because we have to trade
models using new product it's pretty
much the same stuff there's two left
there's to steer down to zero for Civic
I mean you know how to do that I'm not
helping you with that you know what you
have to death
three people let's let's chill four
things leave that leave that model yeah
I'm kind of tired today when we have one
mater this morning it's nice here so
this tool this one not the other one
so this doesn't have anything set yet
are you actually the colors are switched
you can click on these frames oh man
this is slow
that's trash my browser Maps crashed my
browser okay guys there was too much
data in the maps Oh
Burkhard timber five apps let's try
again
making
yeah you guys got a buyer products than
we get I don't know I'm not CEO anymore
rats
WebGL hit a snag oh I know what happened
stupid tensorflow used all my GPU memory
so I was like zoom in here see this they
see this one let's see what this picture
looks like so you can click on this and
that's that frame Wow look it's a
picture of a San Francisco Street let's
see if we can line it up with satellite
imagery it's the right one there oh yeah
you can see it winds up well with the
satellite imagery yeah pretty nice um
yeah so that's it so we have to talk
about on today's scope is Trump use the
neon and I strongly doubt Trump who's
the neon I will do let's do let's do a
few more we'll do some questions will do
is this random question time that'll get
us up to 30 minutes yo yes I need some
r-tx it can anybody get me a RT X 28 et
eyes I'd buy some on what is eating
stream oh we do love eating stream Wow
Tesla's down imma buy some Tesla stock a
buying big Tesla stock here's here's a
scam here's we do a three line right
allegations crash cash low price be
barred from so it's okay no no it was
not going to jail but here's here's
here's some Elon level thinking here
here's an idea
Elon gets barred from serving as an
officer at a public company he's kicked
out of being CEO of Tesla the share
price plummets then he gets the Saudis
to buy Tesla to take Tesla private and
then he comes back on a CEO the share
price goes back up good scam right take
that as you see Sarah fight you
I don't know man Oh politics is for
losers
naturally CTA soon TM especially amazing
clemency that's it I'm doing a right
what else what else we got we got good
questions
you're a PHP programmer bro no one's
coded in PHP since 2004 and Facebook
though Facebook Google I used to hate
Google s I hated Facebook ever since I
quit
where's twitch now I don't winches
anymore
I don't know stop light detection yeah
someday
Tesla hasn't shipped it yet either guys
if you live in a country where you have
to pay taxes you should lobby your
government rust bro what would I do with
the frost you code we code in one light
we really just code in Python yeah you
code Python FCW and I would shiver the
app ok guys real news we took pandas off
of Amazon the shipper app is never gonna
be updated sorry
did I make the ps3 jailbreak we're
definitely not talking about that
reactive elephants I don't know apply I
don't deal with this anymore I do
research I show you these cute little
things can I work at coming yeah you can
apply you know I would I did it it was
like give me a job at comma a I because
I like people so I really think about
what they're doing but maybe the new
administration will change it to careers
at comma AI or admin or get careers
that's the word that's like the
politically correct euphemism for the
two and a half years you're gonna spend
right yeah I got to know things right
now that's the old regime I don't know
about the new G man can you go somewhere
to learn more about big model yeah check
out exception check out
the papers just that a thoughts on going
I think it's disgustingly verbose I like
Haskell
the problem with Haskell is that those
people have like you know they value
mathematical purity more than working
programs they've got any working
programs but like mathematical purity
and then working programs have you met
the new CEO yeah it's Ricardo you've met
him
hello oh yeah what iris code my thoughts
on the Cardiff five is pretty good it's
pretty good it was the whole thing yet I
wouldn't say it's like like like
kamikaze mind-blowing but I'm decently
happy with it what do I think of solid
what is solid wait wait you are PHP
programmer I know that scam you're lying
to me I don't know what any of that
means
check out destroy all software comm they
have some pretty good like paradigms
this seems like I don't know nikka
substitutional principle it seems
needlessly complex okay you're banned
you're bad you're just bad good bad I
did a good big model on your Roomba no
Roomba socks didn't use it anymore
has it been 30 minutes yeah let's say 26
minutes you guys got four more minutes
for question you do Java what would I do
with job solids number one on a hacker
news right now oh oh solid reshape the
web as we know it let's let's let's
explore solve
solid was created by the inventor of the
World Wide Web
okay so first off this concerns me here
right this is is a appeal to Authority
right so you know if you talk about like
fallacies okay
this concerns me as well I don't want a
programming language that empowers users
like I don't even know what that means
this is for everyone what does this mean
okay build on solid this literally just
looks like it's designed to be like
marketed they have a they got some
influential guy to stick his name on it
this is this is complete BS if it's
feel-good marketing this is for everyone
right how it works
you own your data you decide where to
store your data you give people apps
when I see oh I see oh now I'm going to
the etherium hackathon next weekend guys
okay listen oh this is complete garbage
let's see what happened you saying about
it after reading what little okay now
what solid doesn't seem to work
following instructions for how to
authenticate my singulars all right oh
no I'm not up on the latest JavaScript
frameworks I use jQuery you are bought I
know but do the new comma a I have new
plans do I like go like no I think it's
insanely verbose I like rust
I like rust I like what they're trying
to do I think the concept of like the
way they do memory management was like
ownership is nice but it's really hard
to code it like it's hard to think about
do I like see no one like see I like
Python
Oakland style side slideshows on the Bay
Bridge I don't know what that means
any ml resources recommendations bro
like people ask me these kind of
questions like I don't know
google it PI make your life easy are you
geo hot I don't know man are you geo hot
we're all I have Secretariat I do like
pizzas too
all right thank you all for joining this
scope e I will leave you with
on research on the next prop model to
evaluate no bubble game recommendations
get off all mobile games oh look at that
since that solid that model Asst we are
all do hot that's right what version of
Python Python to all toast yeah toast no
they don't put no and I will take a
minute to talk about this toast doesn't
put butter on the toast you have to put
your own butter on the toast and then
when with a friend you know I'm the kind
of person who mostly for the most part
just like like whatever you know they
don't put butter and you toast the best
their policy you know everyone has a
right to conduct business throw away but
she asked she's like can you put butter
on the toast and the toast people said
no that it was against their policy but
they could bring us out softer butter
and they brought us out softer butter
and this made the whole thing worse and
then I went to another diner and they
had butter where there was two pieces of
wax paper okay um thoughts on migration
to Python three Python three is the
single greatest disaster in programming
language history now it's sadly kind of
is but it has burned up probably over a
million hours of developer time and
Python 3 is just a tragedy where nobody
wins I love butter on toast to you think
common need a C programmer to work with
hardware ok you could apply give me a
job of come III I do research I don't
work with hardware's ok bye bye scobie's